Kevin Devlin

Full Stack Web Developer -Lakewood, CO 80226 2394054064 github.com/azwethinkweizkd https://www.kevindevlin.dev/ www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-devlin-b67b3a7a/ kevindevlin11@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a versatile full-stack developer with a solid foundation in JavaScript, C#, React.js, and Node. My skills extend to databases, CI/CD, and cloud platforms (AWS, Azure). My reputation is built on problem-solving, quick learning, and effective team communication. At Novus Home Mortgage, I began as a frontend developer and transitioned to a full-stack role that was C#/EF Core focused. With a diverse skill set and extensive experience, I'm well-prepared to tackle complex full-stack development projects, ensuring seamless stack operation.

Skills

Strong: JavaScript • C# • React.JS • Remix.js • Node • npm• Entity Framework Core • Express

Experienced: HTML5 • CSS3 • MySQL • Git • Tailwind • ChakraUI • Go • HTMX • Agile • CI/CD • Terraform • Encompass

Tools: GitHub • GitKraken • Postman • AWS • Azure • Netlify • Heroku

Personal: Problem-solving • Fast-learner • Communication • Team Member

Work Experience

Novus Home Mortgage | Software Developer | Jun. 2022 - Oct. 2023

Started position as a frontend web developer role working with React.js and eventually became more of a full stack role developing the backend with Entity Framework Code. During my time with Novus I developed new applications for daily operations of mortgage loan origination, maintained and improved legacy code, and reviewed and approved coworkers pull requests. Created a new lead generation website in Remix.js for realtors to upload lists of potential homebuyers, and post that list to our internal API.

3DSystems | Biomedical Designer | Nov. 2014 - Jun. 2022

Designed patient specific guides and models for specialized surgery. Manufactured 3D printed medical devices, and performed quality inspections. Hosted web meetings with surgeons to aid in surgical planning by gathering input of expected product. Organized deliverables queue system.

Projects

Adventure Time | Fullstack Developer & Scrum master | <u>Adventure Time</u>

A web application that records and shares recent outdoor trips for other like minded users to connect and explore the great outdoors together

- > Personally built many features on the app, notably the API call to autocomplete national park information and drop down a menu for users to input their recent adventure correctly
- > Was held accountable for managing the code to keep branches clean and consistent.
- > Uncovered, tracked down, and resolved bugs that resulted in a negative user experience or incomplete views.

Kitchen Forager | Fullstack Developer | Kitchen Forager

Find a delicious new recipe by inputting the items already in your kitchen.

- > Utilized axios to make an API call on the back-end and respond with information to the front-end.
- > Wrote logic to gather and store information to send to the back-end of the application.
- > Styled UI with Bootstrap and Icons for a favorable user experience on desktop and mobile.

Education

University of Denver

- Certificate in Full Stack Development

Florida Gulf Coast University

- Biomedical Engineering

2007 - 2013

2021